Guide to the George Starkovich Ephemera Collection
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
George Starkovich ephemera collection
1942-2000
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
0305
Starkovich, George
4.65 cubic feet (24 boxes)
Ephemeral materials covering topics such as U.S. Community party and various labor unions
George Starkovich was a senior gardener at the University of Washington and the local president of Washington Federation of State Employees Local 1488 president. He was very active as a planner and participant in the 1999 World Trade Organization Seattle Ministerial Conference protests. George Starkovich began working as a gardener at the University of Washington in January of 1965, and quickly became involved in an organizing drive on behalf of his union, WFSE Local 1488. Starkovich was an experienced union organizer who had served as secretary of a miner’s union and shop steward at a plywood plant in Bellingham.
Organized into 2 accessions:
Accession No. 0305-001, George Starkovich collection of sociopolitical pamphlets and papers, 1935-1957
Accession No. 0305-002, George Starkovich materials regarding the WTO 1999 Seattle Ministerial Conference protests, 1999-2000
Ephemeral materials covering topics such as U.S. Community party and various labor unions. Contains pamphlets and papers related to sociopolitical issues like women, immigrants, workers, and civil rights from the 1930s through 1950s. Flyers, newsletters, meeting agendas, and newsclippings relating to George Starkovich's role as a planner and participant in the 1999 World Trade Organization Seattle Ministerial Conference protests.
No restrictions on access.
Starkovich, George$vArchives; Labor union members$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$vArchives; Labor leaders$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$vArchives; Washington Federation of State Employees$xHistory$vSources; AFSCME$xHistory$vSources; Labor$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$xHistory$vSources; Labor unions$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$xHistory$vSources; Labor movement$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$xHistory$vSources; World Trade Organization.$bMinisterial Conference $n (3rd :$d1999 :$cSeattle, Wash.)$xHistory$vSources; Demonstrations$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$xHistory$vSources; Communism$zUnited States$xHistory$vSources; Socialism$zUnited States$xHistory$vSources; Newspaper clippings; Agendas (administrative records); Publications (documents); Reports; Tracts (Ephemera); Newsletters; Labor literature; Starkovich, George$vArchives; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Communist Party of the United States of America; International Woodworkers of America; International Longshoremen's Association; Progressive Citizens of America; Civil Rights Congress (U.S.); Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions; Civic Activism
- George Starkovich collection of sociopolitical pamphlets and papers, 1935-1957; 0305-001; 4.44 cubic feet 23 boxes
  Series 1 contains organizational records of the Civil Rights Congress, A.F.L & C.I.O Committee, Communist Party of the U.S.A, and others. Series 2 contains pamphlets and papers related to sociopolitical issues like women, immigrants, workers, and civil rights from the 1930s through 1950s. Additionally, the pamphlets and papers cover American concerns following World War II and during the rise of Cold War tensions.
  No restrictions on access.
  Gift of Mr. Starkovich, 1963-01-28
  - Organizational Records, Series 1
    - American Committee for the Protection of the Foreign-Born, Undated (Box 1)
      Proceedings of Conference
    - [Anonymous], Undated (Box 1)
      includes circulars with announcements sponsored by many organizations
    - Civil Rights Congress, Undated (Box 1)
    - C.I.O - A.F.L., Undated (Box 1)
    - Committee for a Democratic Far Easter Policy Conference on China and the Far East, Undated (Box 1)
    - Communist Party of the U.S.A, Undated (Box 1)
    - Communist Party of the U.S.A, Undated (Box 1)
    - Communist Party of the U.S.A, Undated (Box 1)
    - Communist Party of the U.S.A (Jefferson School), Undated (Box 1)
    - Communist Party of the U.S.A (Northwest District and King County), Undated (Box 1)
    - Communist Party of the U.S.A (Northwest District and King County), Undated (Box 1)
    - International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, Undated (Box 1)
    - International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, Undated (Box 1)
    - International Workers of America, Undated (Box 1)
    - International Workers of America "Newspapers", Undated (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (A-D), Undated (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (F-J), Undated (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (L-M), Undated (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (N-P), Undated (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (U-Y), Undated (Box 2)
    - Northwest Citizens Defense Committee Newsletter, Undated (Box 2)
    - Pacific Northwest Labor School, Undated (Box 2)
    - Progressive Citizens of America, Undated (Box 2)
    - Progressive Party, Undated (Box 2)
    - United Independent Socialist Conference, Undated (Box 2)
    - Washington Commonwealth Federation (Minutes), Undated (Box 2)
    - Washington Pension Union, Undated (Box 2)
    - World Trade Union Conference, Undated (Box 2)
  - Pamphlets and Small Publications, Series 2
    - Working Class Unity-Bulwark Against Fascism; Dimitroff; International Publishers, Undated (Box 2)
    - New Tasks In the Fight For Peace; Labor Youth League, 1935 (Box 2)
    - Stalin's Life; Dyson Carter; Contemporary Publishers, June, 1953 (Box 2)
    - This is Artukovic; Gaffney, Starcevic, McHugh and Staff, 1943 (Box 2)
    - The Trial of Dr. Aloysius Stepinac: Archbishop of Zagreb; Betty Wallace; The British Yugoslav, Undated (Box 2)
    - The Korean Crisis; Committee for Democratic Far Eastern Policy, 1947 (Box 2)
    - The Truth about Soviet Russia; Sidney & Beatrice Webb; Contemporary Publishers, Undated (Box 2)
    - The F.B.I. vs. The Bill of Rights; Elmer Larson Communist Party, USA, Undated (Box 2)
    - Statement On Our Foreign Situation; Ernest. T. Weir, February, 1953 (Box 2)
    - The Korean Crisis; Committee for a Democratic Far Eastern Policy, January, 1951 (Box 2)
    - The Famous Speeches of the Eight Chicago Anarchists in Court Lucy E. Parsons, Undated (Box 2)
    - The Rank and File is on Trial!; National Union of Marine Cooks and Stewards, CIO, Undated (Box 2)
    - History of the American Negro People 1619-1918; Elizabeth Lawson; Workers Book Shop, Undated (Box 2)
    - History of the American Negro People 1619-1918; Workers Book Shop, 1939 (Box 2)
    - Questions & Answers on the Woman Question; Edited by Irene Epstein & Doxey A. Wilkerson; The Jefferson School of Social Science, 1941 (Box 2)
    - The Soviet White Paper on The North Atlantic Pact; Soviet Russia Today, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Action Against Jim Crow: UPWA's Fight for Equal Rights; Anti-Discrimination Department, March, 1949 (Box 2)
    - Who Are the Traitors to America?; Basil Maddy; Union Labor, Undated (Box 2)
    - Fascist Spain Menace to World Peace; Milton Wolff; New Century Publishers, March, 1947 (Box 3)
    - IRELAND and the IRISH in the U.S.A; James Larkin, T.D.; Transport Workers Union of America, C.I.O, July, 1947 (Box 3)
    - Defend America by Smashing Hitlerism; William Z. Foster; New Century Publishers, September, 1941 (Box 3)
    - 21 questions about WAR and PEACE; Eugene Dennis; New Century Publishers, August, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Geneva Road to Peace; Joseph Clark; New Century Publishers, September, 1955 (Box 3)
    - The Atom Bomb and You; Joseph Clark & William Weinstone; New Century Publishers, September, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Beware of the War Danger!; William Z. Foster; New Century Publishers, April, 1948 (Box 3)
    - Universal Military Training (UMT); Leo Cooper; New Century Publishers, March, 1948 (Box 3)
    - The Rise of Socialism in the Soviet Union; D.Z. Manuilsky; New Century Publishers, August, 1935 (Box 3)
    - The War Mongers; William Z. Foster; New Century Publishers, November, 1947 (Box 3)
    - Daughters of America: Ella Reeve Bloor & Anita Whitney; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn; International Publishers, June, 1942 (Box 3)
    - In the Dungeons of Mussolini; Carlo Ross; Italian Patronati, March, 1936 (Box 3)
    - The United Front Against Fascism and War; G. Dimitroff; International Publishers, October, 1935 (Box 3)
    - American Democracy and The War; William Z. Foster; International Publishers, February, 1942 (Box 3)
    - Socialist Reconstruction of Society; Daniel De Leon; Industrial Union Party, 1934 (Box 3)
    - Japanese Imperialism Exposed: The Secret Tanaka Document; International Publishers, 1942 (Box 3)
    - Speeches by A. Y. Vyshinsky; Information Bulletin of the Embassy of the Union of Soviet Specialist Republics, September-October, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Toward Bright Tomorrows; Roosevelt Ward; Challenge, June, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Slavic Americans in the fight for Victory and Peace; George Pirinsky; American Slav Congress, March, 1946 (Box 3)
    - From Defense to Attack; William Z. Foster Workers Library Publishers, Inc., February, 1942 (Box 3)
    - They Still Carry On! Native Fascists: how to spot them and stop them U.S. War Department National Federation for Constitutional Liberties (NFCL), 1945 (Box 3)
    - Destroy Hitler! Free Germany!; International Publishers, 1942 (Box 3)
    - Going Left Alex Bittleman Workers Library Publishers, Inc., March, 1936 (Box 3)
    - Broaden the Fight for Peace and Democracy! Joseph Rockman New Century Publishers, September, 1952 (Box 3)
    - The Twilight of World Capitalism William Z. Foster International Publishers, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Fascism or Freedom; Watch Tower Bible an Tract Society International Bible Students Association, 1939 (Box 3)
    - Australians In Spain Nettie Palmer & Len Fox Current Book Distributors, 1948 (Box 3)
    - 300 Million Slaves and Serfs Jurgen Kuczynski International Publishers, 1943 (Box 3)
    - Speeches by A.Y. Vyshinsky; Information Bulletin of the Embassy of the Union of Society Specialist Republics, December, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Socialism: What's In It For You A.B. Magil New Century Publishers, April, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Two Years of Heroic Struggle of the Spanish People Georgi Dimitroff International Publishers, August, 1938 (Box 3)
    - Peace and Price Cuts Too! Felix Baran New Century Publishers, April, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Youth Marches Towards Socialism Wolf Michal International Publishers, 1936 (Box 4)
    - The Menace The Menace Of a New World War; William Z. Foster; New Century Publishers, March, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Must There Be War; Joseph Clark; New Century Publishers, December, 1951 (Box 4)
    - Your Questions Answered; William Z. Foster International Publishers, June, 1939 (Box 4)
    - What's What About the War; William Z. Foster; National Election Campaign Committee, Communist Party of USA, Workers Library Publishers, Inc., July, 1940 (Box 4)
    - The War Crisis; William Z. Foster; International Publishers, January, 1940 (Box 4)
    - The Path to Peace; New World Review, September, 1951 (Box 4)
    - Is Socialism the Answer; William Irvine; Contemporary Publishers, 1945 (Box 4)
    - Peace or War: The People against the Warmakers!; Eugene Dennis; New Century Publishers, May, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Negotiations: The Way to Peace; Jessica Smith; New World Review, 1954 (Box 4)
    - USA-USSR Cooperation And World Peace; The National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, 1951 (Box 4)
    - Americans, Russians, and Peace; American Russian Institute, 1949 (Box 4)
    - Agents of Peace; Albert E. Kahn; The Hour Publishers, Undated (Box 4)
    - Nazis Preferred; Moses Miller; New Century Publishers, June, 1950 (Box 4)
    - Intellectuals in the Fight for Peace; Howard Fast; Masses & Mainstream, Inc., June, 1949 (Box 4)
    - Reaction Beats its War Drums; William Z. Foster; New Century Publishers, May, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Victory and After; Earl Browder; New Century Publishers, 1942 (Box 4)
    - The Treatment of Defeated Germany; V. J. Jerome; New Century Publishers, May, 1945 (Box 4)
    - Pattern For American Fascism; John L. Spivak; New Century Publishers, September, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Nazi Army or Peaceful Germany; Alan Max; New Century Publishers, May, 1952 (Box 4)
    - New Opportunities in the Fight for Peace and Democracy; Andrew Stevens; New Century Publishers, December, 1953 (Box 4)
    - For Freedom and Peace; Paul Robeson; Council on African Affairs, June, 1949 (Box 4)
    - How to Grow a Peace Garden: the story of a flower that reached around the world; Mary Phillips Peace Garden Nursery, 1954 (Box 4)
    - The Struggle for Peace and Democracy In U.S.A; George Pirinsky American Slav Congress, 1947 (Box 4)
    - "...To Live In Peace"; New York Communist Party, Undated (Box 4)
    - Rights of Women Defense of Children Peace: Women's International Democratic Federation; The Women's International Democratic Federation, Undated (Box 4)
    - Those Responsible for the Second World War: Veritas; D. Tomitch Agora Publishing Co. Inc., 1947 (Box 4)
    - Falsifiers of History: An Historical Document on the Origins of World War II; Frederick L. Schuman; Committee for the Promotion of Peace, Undated (Box 4)
    - Peace Can be Won!; Gus Hall; New Century Publishers, January, 1951 (Box 5)
    - What is the World of Council of Peace?, Undated (Box 5)
    - Minnesota Sings for Pace, Undated (Box 5)
    - Don't Be a Jerk!: Jerks are a Noosence; Hedi Seligsohn; The League for Fair Play, Inc., 1947 (Box 5)
    - New Perspectives for American Socialism: The case for unity; Max Shachtman; Independent Socialist League, Undated (Box 5)
    - China's Foreign Trade Soars Why can't Americans Benefit?; Maud Russel; Far East Reporter, Undated (Box 5)
    - Report on War Crimes in Korea; The Commission of International Association of Democratic lawyers, April, 1952 (Box 5)
    - Britain's Cultural Heritage; Sam Aaronovitch; Arena Publication, Undated (Box 5)
    - The Truth About Korea; Southern California Chapter of the National Council Arts, Sciences and Professions, Undated (Box 5)
    - The Mask is Off; Jack Woddis; Thames Publications, June, 1954 (Box 5)
    - Hungary--Christian or Pagan: An Eye-witness Report; Kenneth Leslie New Christian Books, Undated (Box 5)
    - Report from China; Hugh Hardyman; Southern California Peace Crusade, Undated (Box 5)
    - Hungary In Travail; Jessica Smith; New World Review, December, 1956 (Box 5)
    - 8 Million Demand Freedom!: What about it, Gen. Smuts?; I. B. Tabata; Council on African Affairs, 1946 (Box 5)
    - Put Canada First; Tim Buck; National Committee, Labor Progressive Party, May, 1954 (Box 5)
    - The Yugoslav People Fight to Live; Josip Broz Tito; United Committee of South-Slavic Americans, 1944 (Box 5)
    - What's Happening in Korea?; Richard Morris; New Century Publishers, 1944 (Box 5)
    - What Price Philippine Independence; George Phillips; New Century Publishers, Undated (Box 5)
    - Labor in Australia; Lloyd Ross; America Council, Institute of Pacific Relations, 1943 (Box 5)
    - Your Tagore For To-Day; Hirankumar Sanyal; Peoples Publishing House Bombay, Undated (Box 5)
    - What Path For India; Gerhard Hagelberg; Far East Reporter, Undated (Box 5)
    - The Lesson of Czecho Slovakia; Robert G. Spivack; The American League for Peace and Democracy, November, 1938 (Box 5)
    - Women in New China; Foreign Language Press, Peking, 1949 (Box 5)
    - Moa Tse-Tung On the Chinese Revolution; Chen Po-ta; Foreign Language Press, Peking, 1953 (Box 5)
    - Internationalism and Nationalism; Liu Shao-chi; Foreign Language Press, Peking, Undated (Box 5)
    - Mind the Living Conditions of the Masses and Attend to the Methods of Work; Mao Tse-Tung; Foreign Language Press, Peking, 1953 (Box 5)
    - On Methods of Leadership; Moa Tse-Tung Foreign; Language Press, Peking, 1955 (Box 5)
    - On the Rectification of Incorrect Ideas in the Party; Moa Tse-Tung; Foreign Language Press, Peking, 1953 (Box 5)
    - India's Progress; Far East Reporter, Undated (Box 5)
    - Enemies of the Peace: Profile of the 'Hate-Russia' Gang; Sender Garlin; New Century Publishers, November, 1945 (Box 5)
    - Indise Liberated Poland; Anna Louise Strong; National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Undated (Box 6)
    - Israel and Dollar Diplomacy; Victor Perlo; New Century Publishers, March, 1953 (Box 6)
    - Resistance: Against Fascist Enslavement in South America; The Council on African Affairs, 1953 (Box 6)
    - People's China Stands For Peace; Committee for a Democratic Far Eaten Policy, December, 1950 (Box 6)
    - The United States and Mexico: Two Nations--One Ideal; Vincente Lombardo Toledano ;Council for Pan-American Diplomacy, 1942 (Box 6)
    - The Truth About Guatemala; Helen Simon Travis & A. B. Magil; New Century Publishers, April, 1954 (Box 6)
    - Murder Inc. In Greece; Olive Sutton; New Century Publishers, April, 1948 (Box 6)
    - Slav People's Vow...Never Again!; Mary Pirinsky; The National Committee of American Slav Congress, March, 1945 (Box 6)
    - The Communists and the Liberation of Europe; Maxine Levi; New Century Publishers, March, 1945 (Box 6)
    - 25 Años De Lucha Es Mi Respuesta A La Persecución; Juan Saez Corales; New Century Publishers, August, 1955 (Box 6)
    - What are we doing In China; Joseph North; New Century Publishers, December, 1945 (Box 6)
    - The Six-Year Plan In Poland: of economic development and building the foundations of socialism; Boleslaw Beirut & Hilary Minc; Książka i Wiedza, Warszawa, 1950 (Box 6)
    - Labor Unions in the Far East; Eleanor H. Lattimore; America Council, Institute of Pacific Relations, 1945 (Box 6)
    - Indo-China and World Peace; Richard Walker; New Century Publishers, June, 1954 (Box 6)
    - New Horizons for Young Canada; Tim Buck; National Committee, Labor-Progressive Party, March, 1953 (Box 6)
    - Yugoslav Muslim' Message To India; Dr. Zajim Sarac; New Age Printing Press, Undated (Box 6)
    - Thirty Years of the Communist Party of China; Hu Chiao-Mu; Lawrence & Wishart LTD., 1951 (Box 6)
    - Introductory Remarks to "The Communist"; Mao Tse-Tung; Foreign Language Press, Peking, 1953 (Box 6)
    - Hungary's Fight for Democracy; Zoltan Deak; New Century Publishers, August, 1947 (Box 6)
    - On Practice; Mao Tse-Tung Foreign Language Press, Peking, 1951 (Box 6)
    - Turning Point in China Mao Tse-Tung; New Century Publishers, 1948 (Box 6)
    - The Marriage Law of the People's Republic of China; Foreign Language Press, Peking, 1950 (Box 6)
    - A Message from New China; Soong Ching Ling, Undated (Box 6)
    - Bengal's Forgotten Warriors; Niranjan Sen; People's Publishing House, December, 1945 (Box 6)
    - How to be a Good Communist; Liu-Shao-Chi; New Century Publishers, November, 1952 (Box 6)
    - On Practice; Mao Tse-Tung; International Publishers, Undated (Box 6)
    - On People's Democratic Rule; Mao Tse-Tung; New Century Publishers, July, 1950 (Box 6)
    - On Inner-Party Struggle; Liu Shao-Chi; New Century Publishers, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Philippine Emergency; Catherine Porter; America Council, Institute of Pacific Relations, 1941 (Box 6)
    - A Palestine Solution; Andrei Gromyko; Morning Freiheit Association, May, 1947 (Box 7)
    - The People Rule in Yugoslavia; William Rust; The People's Press Printing Society, Ltd., Undated (Box 7)
    - Church and State in Eastern Europe; Rev. Stanley Evans; New Central European Observer, Undated (Box 7)
    - Africa Fights for Freedom; Alphaeus Hunton; New Century Publishers, March, 1950 (Box 7)
    - Nigeria: Why we Fight for Freedom; Amanke Okafor; Amanke Okafor, January, 1950 (Box 7)
    - Who is Stalling In Korea; Maud Russel, May, 1952 (Box 7)
    - Formosa: Fact and Fiction; John W. Powell, Undated (Box 7)
    - Twenty Thousand Clergyman For Armenia; American Church Committee for Armenia, Undated (Box 7)
    - Canadian Independence and a People's Parliament: Canada's path to Socialism; Program of the Labor-Progressive Party, June, 1954 (Box 7)
    - The Socialist Road for Britain; Central Books Ltd., Undated (Box 7)
    - The Armenian Crisis, 1912-1914; Roderic H. Davison; The Armenian National Council of America, October, 1948 (Box 7)
    - Visit To India; N. A. Bulganin & N.S. Khrushchev; New Century Publishers, February, 1956 (Box 7)
    - Visit to Burma and Afghanistan; N.A. Bulganin & N. S. Khrushchev; New Century Publishers, February, 1956 (Box 7)
    - A Friendship Mission: The Record of a Visit to the Soviet Union-1960; Richard and Aileen Morford; National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, June, 1960 (Box 7)
    - Report From Europe; The Rank and File Delegation of the International Longshoremen's & Warehousemen's Union, 1949 (Box 7)
    - The Yankee Occupation of Canada; Tim Buck; Labor-Progressive Party, February, 1950 (Box 7)
    - Where is the C.C.F. Going; Charles Sims; Labor-Progressive Party, October, 1950 (Box 7)
    - Hands Off Korea and Formosa; Gus Hall; Century Publishers, July, 1950 (Box 7)
    - The Works of Mao Tse-Tung; Guozi Shudian; Suchou Hutung, Undated (Box 7)
    - Pakistan And Indian National Unity; G. Adhikari; Labour Monthly, Undated (Box 7)
    - Stories of Chinese Young Pioneers; Chang Tien-Yi; Foreign Language Press, 1954 (Box 7)
    - The Suppressed Testament of Lenin Leon Trotsky; Pioneer Publishers, November, 1946 (Box 7)
    - Report on the Organizational Problems of the Party and Soviet Construction; L.M. Kaganovich; Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the U.S.S.R., Undated (Box 7)
    - The Communist Manifesto; Karl Marx & Friedrich Engels; International Publishers, 1932 (Box 7)
    - Moscow Session of the Council of Foreign Ministers 1947; V. M. Molotov; Soviet News (Box 7)
    - Value, Price and Profit; Karl Marx & Friedrich Engels; Chicago Charles H. Kerr & Company Co-operative, Undated (Box 7)
    - The Foundation of the Communist International; V. I. Lenin; International Publishers, 1937 (Box 7)
    - Lenin Speaks to the Youth; International Publishers, 1936 (Box 7)
    - State and Revolution; V.I. Lenin; International Publishers, 1932 (Box 7)
    - The State; V. I. Lenin; New Century Publishers, May, 1947 (Box 7)
    - The Communist Party of the Soviet Union; A. Zhdanov; International Publishers, June, 1939 (Box 7)
    - Constitution (Fundamental Law) of The Union of Soviet Socialist Republics; National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Undated (Box 8)
    - Interview with Pravda Correspondent; J. V. Stalin; Foreign Languages Publishing House Moscow, 1951 (Box 8)
    - The Tasks of the Youth Leagues; V. I. Lenin; Foreign Languages Publishing House Moscow, 1953 (Box 8)
    - 31 Years of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics; V. M. Molotov; New Century Publishers, December, 1948 (Box 8)
    - Wage-Labour And Capital; Karl Marx; International Publishers, Undated (Box 8)
    - On the Threshold of Communism; G. M. Malenkov; New Century Publishers, November, 1952 (Box 8)
    - Soviet Leaders Speak for Communism and Peace; V.M. Molotov, L.P Beria, N.A. Bulganin, L. M. Kaganovich,& K. Y. Voroshilov; New Century Publishers, December, 1952 (Box 8)
    - Joseph Stalin: A Short Biography; The Marx-Engels-Lenin Institute; New York Workers Library Publishers, Inc., October, 1941 (Box 8)
    - Report on the Directives of the 20th Congress of the C.P.S.U For the Sixth Five-Year Plan for the Development of the U.S.S.R 1956-1960; N.A. Bulganin; Foreign Languages Publishing House - Moscow (Box 8)
    - Report of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union to the 20th Party Congress; N.S. Khrushchov; Foreign Languages Publishing House - Moscow, 1956 (Box 8)
    - Speech at the 20th Congress of the C.P.S.U; A. I. Kirichenko; Foreign Languages Publishing House - Moscow, 1956 (Box 8)